OLIVIA "OLLIE" CLINE

PASTRY CHEF AND ASPIRING UX DESIGNER



https://www.linkedin.com/in/olivia-cline-50a5b01ba/



https://olliedesigns.site

EXPERIENCE

Pastry Chef

Patisserie 46

4552 Grand Ave, Minneapolis, MN 55419 May 2022 - Present

- Collaborating with a small team in a large production kitchen to design and execute haute desserts with a high level of detail
- Continually improving recipes to create better yield percentages, less waste, and better products

Concierge

Spice Islands Marketplace, CIA 2555 Main Street, St Helena, CA 94574 **Jan 2022 - Apr 2022**

- Guiding tours historical tours, providing information and contacting staff on behalf of visitors for appointments and questions
- Assisting in the Spice Islands Marketplace to answer customer questions, restock and organize items, and use the register to process transactions and returns

Baking and Pastry Extern

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Patisserie 46

4552 Grand Ave, Minneapolis, MN 55419

- Assisting current employees in a large production kitchen to learn about the baking industry
- Learning new techniques and handling different situations and conflicts in day to day pastry work

Sales Associate

Aug 2016 - May 2017

Plantorium Greenhouse and Nursery 2933 Co Rd 54G, Fort Collins, CO 80524

- Matching plant characteristics to customers based on customer descriptions and situations and making suggestions based on customer needs
- Caring for plants to ensure quality, freedom from pests and other types of damage

EDUCATION

Career Foundry

Ux Design Course

Nov 2022 - Present

Expected graduation Sep 2023

The Culinary Institute of America

Baking and Pastry A.O.S

Sep 2020 - Apr 2022

Graduated with high honors

PROFILE

Pastry chef turned Ux designer, I a motivated to create products and services that create meaningful, lasting, and usable impact in people's lives. My background as a pastry chef allows unique introspect into user and customer frustrations, creating opportunities to create experiences that are delightful, engaging, and intuitive.

SKILLS

DESIGN SKILLS

- Prototyping
- · User Testing
- · Competitive analysis and research
- Wire Framing
- Graphic Design

FUNDAMENTAL DESIGN SKILLS

- Sketching
- Illustration
- · Creative direction
- Concept development
- Detail orientated

GENERAL SKILLS

- · Self motivated
- Communicative
- Decisive
- Active listener
- Avid learner
- Open to criticism
- · Continual problem solving

TOOLS - proficient

- Marvel
- Procreate

TOOLS - learning

- Blender
- Figma
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop